Ayesha Arshad

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

ayesharshad4567@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

SUMMARY

A front-end web developer experienced in using JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS to build all aspects of the user experience, with a love for clean code, and a passion for responsive website design. Proficient in multiple languages, frameworks, and technologies, and capable of progressing quickly and efficiently.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, BootStrap

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, Figma, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE June 2022 – Present

Remote Full-Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spend 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Develop skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

COMSATS University of Information Technology Islamabad

February, 2016 - January, 2020

Bachelor, Software Engineering

- FYP was an android and web application safety system to prevent and report accidents.
- Awards and Honor: Merit Scholarship for holding the top position in the batch, scored 3.58 CGPA.

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Front-end Web Developer

Month, Year - Present

AebinAR —A webinar website. Platform to engage with audience through virtual conferences and events.

Built with: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

PokePlayCards— A fun "Pokemon" card site enlisting "Pokemons" and their abilities.

• Built with: JavaScript, Html, CSS, RESTful API, Webpack

<u>BookStore</u>— A site that creates your bookstore. You can add and remove books from your store.

• Built with: CSS, React, Redux, RESTful API

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) August 2022 - Present

Mentoring junior web developers, and providing technical support through code reviews.

• Provide advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

Luqon IT Solutions Pvt.

Quality Assurance Intern

Rawalpindi, Pakistan

December, 2020 - March 2021

- Worked with the development team to identify potential bugs to improve customer satisfaction.
- Reported at least 10 new bugs every day to eliminate as many bugs as possible before deployment to save the company money and time.